<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>genetics on DL Filer</title>
    <link>https://daynefiler.github.io/categories/genetics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in genetics on DL Filer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 14:30:16 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://daynefiler.github.io/categories/genetics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Downloading gnomAD</title>
      <link>https://daynefiler.github.io/blog/downloadgnomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 14:30:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daynefiler.github.io/blog/downloadgnomad/</guid>
      <description>Here is a concise guide to downloading gnomAD using gsutil. I am typically working on a server, and (begrudgingly) use conda to manage software. The only real trick here is getting the conda environment setup &amp;ndash; I could have easily called this &amp;ldquo;Using gsutil with conda.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; the actual gsutil utility is pretty easy to use. gsutil, needed for accessing the gnomAD data, is buried within the &amp;lsquo;google-cloud-sdk&amp;rsquo; conda package, not to be confused with the numerous other &amp;lsquo;google-cloud-&amp;rsquo; conda packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G-indexing in VCF files</title>
      <link>https://daynefiler.github.io/blog/gindexing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 13:09:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daynefiler.github.io/blog/gindexing/</guid>
      <description>The gnomAD VCF files give information about the observed genotype counts, eg &amp;ldquo;GC_EAS&amp;rdquo; gives the genotype counts for individuals of East Asian decent as a comma-separated string. The order of the counts is determined by genotype-indexing. The above link gives an excellent discussion of getting the genotype index for the general case, regardless of ploidy number. Below is a brief discussion of haploid and diploid indices.
Genotype-indexing works by first indexing the reference and alternative alleles, starting with the reference allele at 0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
